summary

Full stack software engineer with experience in AngularJS, Ruby on Rails, Rspec, and more. Easy-going, tenacious, hard-working, and adaptable. A lifelong coder, driven to solve new challenges, who absorbs new tools and concepts with ease.

projects

KitHub

Lesson plan platform | https://github.com/philipcolejohnson/kithub

- Three Angular apps with Rails backend featuring a version control algorithm
- Uploading, downloading, and document conversion from docx to markdown
- Live data visualizations using D3.js

Fideligard Historical Portfolio Simulator

A stock-trading simulator-with time travel! | https://github.com/philipcolejohnson/fideligard spa

- Single page app entirely in AngularJS with data from Yahoo Finance API
- · Routing using the ui-router module

Danebook

A social media web app for Scandinavians | https://github.com/philipcolejohnson/project danebook

- MVC Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL backend with AJAX calls
- Photo storage utilizing Amazon S3
- · Model, controller, and feature testing

BetterHome

The eHarmony of neighborhoods | https://github.com/philipcolejohnson/better_home

- Integrates 7 REST APIs (Factual/Google Maps/Socrata/Trulia/Walkscore/Yelp/Zillow)
- Full authentication suite using OmniAuth and Devise
- Delayed jobs with dyno worker for email and scheduled API calls

employment highlights

Masterprep Academy

Teacher/Website Administrator

2015 to 2016

- Instructor and substitute teacher for lower and upper level math classes, English grammar, and SAT Writing
- Created and maintained the masterprepacademy.com website using WordPress, CSS, and HTML

Henry Ford Health System

Detroit, MI

Irvine, CA

Research Coordinator

2013 to 2013

- Coordinated and edited an NIH grant project involving over a dozen researchers in three countries that was awarded more than \$1 million
- · Developed web content for the Infectious Disease fellowship website

Chungdahm Learning

Seoul, Korea

English Instructor

2009 to 2011

- Taught listening, reading, and writing skills to classes of elementary and middle school students
- Lead Master Classes for advanced students on classical English literature and literary essay compositional skills, in preparation for American university classes

Peace Corps

Karakul, Kyrgyzstan

Volunteer

2005 to 2007

- · Overcame insufficient resources, resistance to new methodologies, petulant Russians, and other obstacles while teaching in a remote, rural village
- · Worked with a team to fund, organize, and conduct a leadership camp for more than 50 middle school boys
- · Stoically and diplomatically swallowed boiled sheep eyeballs

education

Viking Code School 2016

Full Stack Boot Camp

New Mexico State University MFA 2014

Fiction Writing

Michigan State University BA 2005

English



skills +

BACKEND

Ruby

Ruby on Rails

SQL

REST APIs

RSpec/Capybara

FRONTEND

AngularJS

HTML5/CSS

Bootstrap

JavaScript

i0uerv

AJAX/XHR

SASS

PROFESSIONAL

Agile

Pair Programming

Git

Writing/Editing

Intercultural Communication

Public Speaking